Daniel Lord

7 Moylan Road, London, W6 8QD 07951620775, danlord1997@gmail.com

Meticulous and creative full-stack software engineer with a first-class Computer Science degree, graduating at the **top of my year**. 5+ years of experience building full stack solutions for the **leading provider of energy trading solutions in Europe** using C#, .Net, and React.

Skills

Languages & Frameworks: C#, .NET (6+, Core, Framework), ASP.NET (MVC/Web API), React, TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, JSON, YAML, NUnit, Moq

Cloud & Tools: AWS (Lambda, API Gateway ,CodePipeline), Azure Pipelines, Kafka, Docker, Azure DevOps, Git, CI/CD, Onion Architecture, Microservices

Professional Experience

Career Break | Scuola Leonardo Da Vinci, Rome | Jul 2024 - present

■ Achieved C1 proficiency in Italian through immersive study. Demonstrated self-discipline, rapid learning, and cultural adaptability.

Software Engineer | Trayport Ltd, London | Jan 2020 - Jul 2024

- Led projects in a 40+ person team across 10+ enterprise codebases, including trading platforms, financial APIs, and internal tools for the **market leader in European energy trading technology**.
- Maintained and enhanced mission-critical trading platforms, **used by 85%+ of screen-based energy traders in Europe**, consistently resolving high-impact issues with speed and precision in time-sensitive, high-stakes environments.
- Spearheaded the migration of a monolithic administrative system to a microservices architecture using C#, .NET, DDD, and Entity Framework, reducing the deployment time from 2 days to a 1 click.
- Developed clean RESTful APIs with .NET and EF, using OAuth2, Redis, and MemoryCache for secure, scalable, and efficient performance in enterprise applications.
- Integrated system health checks, custom metrics, and alerts using Prometheus, Grafana, and Serilog, enabling early detection of production issues and reducing downtime.
- Streamlined deployment processes with AWS and Azure (Amplify, Lambda, API Gateway, Pipelines), automating workflows and accelerating development cycles.
- Took immense pride in mentoring colleagues (two of whom received promotions), focusing on building their confidence, teaching best practices, and fostering a supportive, enjoyable learning environment.
- Deployed scalable, resilient apps using Docker and Kubernetes in production.
- Developed and optimised complex React + TypeScript UIs for trading platforms, focusing on accessibility (WCAG 2.1), performance (lazy loading, memoization), responsive design, and robust test coverage (Jest, Cypress).

Bespoke Consultant | Waterstons Ltd (Microsoft Gold Partner), Durham | Jun 2017 - Jun 2018

- Refined craft as a full stack developer, becoming skilled in C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript and .Net framework, owning projects from conception to completion.
- Grasped complex design patterns from MVC to event sourcing with CQRS, producing clean and

maintainable code.

- Worked in a Kanban-driven agile environment with cross-functional teams (designers, marketers, PMs) to deliver timely frontend solutions.
- Participated in code reviews, pair programming sessions, and daily stand-ups to maintain high code quality.

Education

2015 - 2019 BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Industrial Experience ($\mathbf{1}_{st}$), Newcastle University

Relevant Modules Include: Mathematics for Computer Science, Algorithm Design and Analysis, System and Network Security, Cryptography, Reliability and Fault Tolerance.

- Won the School of Computing academic award for **best overall performance in the year** with an overall grade of 85%, reflecting my affinity and genuine enjoyment of the discipline.
- Achieved an overall mark of 87% on my 15,000-word dissertation entitled "Procedurally Generated Large-Scale Alien Planets", learning valuable research and organisation techniques.
- Understood the fundamentals of all programming languages and how to program in Java, SQL,HTML, CSS, C, C++ and more.

2008 - 2015 The London Oratory School

A Level: Mathematics (A) Chemistry (B) History (C)

AS Level: Ancient History (B) **10 GCSEs:** 5A* grades 5A grades

Achievements

- Earned two Microsoft Certifications: 70-483 Programming in C#, 70-480 Programming HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 with scores of above 80% in both.
- Delivered lectures for Microsoft Scotland to boards of universities in Northern England and Scotland, advocating for the integration of cloud computing technologies into academic environments to enhance learning experiences.
- Honed public speaking and teaching skills through a lecture on Agile development at Hertfordshire University.
- Founded and organised an after-school coding club at St Margaret's CE Primary School. Scrupulously planned and taught lessons in Python.
- Qualified as a British Sub-Aqua Club Sports Diver. This experience taught me how to act reasonably under pressure and not panic.

References

Former Line Manager: Mr Peter Lidford , Head of Web, Trayport Ltd, 2 Gresham Street, London EC2V 7AD, +44 (0)20 7960 5500, peter.lidford@trayport.com

Former Line Manager: Mr Alex Fuller, Principal Developer, Trayport Ltd, 2 Gresham Street, London EC2V 7AD, +44 (0)20 7960 5500, alex.fuller@trayport.com